Discover the hero just beneath the surface.
Ruby Gillman, Teenage Kraken is a animation, family,
fantasy film directed by Kirk DeMicco.
Ruby Gillman, a sweet and awkward high school student, discovers
she's a direct descendant of the warrior kraken queens.
The kraken are sworn to protect the oceans of the world
against the vain, power-hungry mermaids.
Destined to inherit the throne from her commanding grandmother, Ruby must
use her newfound powers to protect those she loves most.
Ruby Gillman (voice), played by Lana Condor.
Agatha Gillman (voice), played by Toni Collette.
Chelsea Van Der Zee (voice), played by Annie Murphy.
Uncle Brill (voice), played by Sam Richardson.
Margo (voice), played by Liza Koshy.
Gordon Lighthouse (voice), played by Will Forte.
Ruby Gillman, Teenage Kraken is a 2023 American animated
comedy film produced by DreamWorks Animation.
Directed by Kirk DeMicco and written by Brian C.
Brown, Elliott DiGuiseppi and Pam Brady, it stars the voices of Lana Condor,
Toni Collette, Annie Murphy, Colman Domingo, and Jane Fonda.
The film follows a shy Kraken girl named Ruby Gillman (Condor)
who is desperate to fit in at Oceanside High.
When she breaks her mother's (Collette) rule by going into the ocean with any would-be friends, she discovers that she is a direct descendant of battle-hardened
krakens who have protected the sea from evil mermaids for generations, and is also destined to inherit the throne from her grandmother (Fonda).
Ruby Gillman, Teenage Kraken had its world premiere at the Annecy International Animation Film Festival
on June 15, 2023, and was released in the United States by Universal Pictures on June 30.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the voice
acting and characters but criticized the screenplay.
It was a box-office failure, grossing $46 million against a $70 million budget.
The film explores themes of high school, ocean, boat, transformation, fisherman.
The tone is lighthearted.